RICHA SHAURBH

2400 4th Ave #567 Seattle WA 98121

+1 (206) 953-3929 richa.shaurabh@gmail.com <u>richasha.github.io/Portfolio</u> linkedin.com/in/richa-shaurabh

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Web/Frontend Developer with 4+ years of professional experience & expertise in a wide array of frontend technologies, like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js & AngularJS, demonstrated in onsite & offshore delivery paradigms, in projects across the telecom domain and digital marketing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering from SRM University, Chennai, India2008 – 2012Web & Mobile Development Certification course from Epicodus, Seattle, USA2017High School from Patna Women's College2008

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LG Soft India

Apr 2015 – Jul 2017

Software Developer

Bangalore, India

- Researched & evaluated LG's frontend framework "Enyo" against newer frameworks & technologies and helped devise a strategy for a major revamp to "Enact": LG's next generation React based JS framework
- Developed Enact framework components that can be used for developing native-quality, cross-device compatible HTML5 apps, as part of a team of developers distributed across US and India
- Recognized department-wide within a month of hire, for developing & optimizing the Camera & Gallery apps for LG Fx0 phone, on top of the Firefox Mobile OS's Gaia User Interface layer using Object Oriented JS.

Tech Mahindra Nov 2013 – Apr 2015

Software Developer

Sydney, Australia & Bangalore, India

- Optus Mobile Network Coverage App Designed & developed a frontend application that showed network tower diagnosis information on a map to customers, using JavaScript, AngularJS & the OpenLayers library
- Also, developed the Customer Complaint Logging feature that can be used by customers to receive response from Optus Engineers.

FLORET Media Jan 2013 – Nov 2013

Web Developer

Bangalore, India

- As one of 10 developers at the startup firm, coordinated directly with several client organizations to analyze requirements and develop responsive websites to aid in their Digital marketing.
- Ramped up quickly on various web development best practices & technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery & AngularJS, to deliver personalized Digital Marketing success for clients.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, React.js, HTML, CSS, SASS, SCSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL **Testing Frameworks:** Jasmine, Karma **Tools:** Git, npm, Sublime Text, Firebase **OS Experience:** MacOS, Windows

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- **UberLibs** An online Library and book borrowing system to help any brick & mortar library launch its services online. Developed using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL, the system displays a beautiful web frontend that lists books by category, shows book covers & descriptions. Registered Library members can create wishlists, borrow books and order book delivery/returns to/from their doorstep.
- Trail finder An easy-to-use website, developed using AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, Google Maps & Trail API, that helps customers search for fun trails in any area by location
- **Doctors Search** A user-friendly web application that allows users to search for Doctors in a certain area based on a medical condition, doctor's name and other similar search criteria using JavaScript and the BetterDoctor API.
- Mykart An E-Commerce website with user interfaces to show product details, product listings and shopping carts.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Epicodus Certified "Web & Mobile Development" Engineer [2017] Met all the certification requirements: JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- Sports Awarded by the State government for winning in the Throwball league for the state of Bihar, India